

Tural Sadigov

Data Scientist/Lead

US Permanent Resident

Contact

San Fransisco Bay area

→ +1 (812) 650 2583

turalsadikov@gmail.com

turalsadigov.github.io

turalsadigov

in tural-sadigov/

Skills

Python	4 yrs.
Git/Github Actions	2 yrs.
Battery Data Science	1.5 years
Data Analysis	8 years
Database management	2 yrs.
Software Development	2 years
R	8 yrs.
Rmarkdown/Quarto	6 yrs.
Web Development	2 years

Summary

Staff Data Scientist and Data Intellegence Lead with a Ph.D. in Applied Mathematics and over 8 years of experience in developing data products, including machine learning models, APIs that serve these models, and web apps/dashboards that integrate various data pipelines and APIs in the backend. Experienced in teaching applied mathematics and data-related courses, such as Statistics, Machine Learning, Probability, and Time Series Analysis (on Coursera). Have mentored graduate students on software projects at UC Berkeley, undergraduate Machine Learning projects in the Statistical Methods in Machine Learning course, and industry colleagues on data science and DevOps practices. Extensively use Python, Git, GitHub Actions, and Posit Connect in daily routines. Creator of a private Python package at Sepion Technologies and a public R package, stats2data, for the Statistical Modeling and Applications course at Hamilton College.

Experience

Staff Data Scientist

Sepion Technologies

02/2023 - Present

Involved in multiple data-related domains, such as Data Science, Data Engineering, DevOps, Software Development, and Machine Learning. Led projects focused on creating and managing PostgreSQL and Amazon Redshift databases, as well as developing custom web applications for internal use. Maintained the Posit Connect server in AWS, deploying various data products. Worked on internal data products to aid scientists throughout the data lifecycle, from collection to visualization to analysis. Created and automated scripts to preprocess data for ML modeling, training, and deploying ML models. Developed an internal Python package. Successfully saved at least 172K in the company budget through negotiation and data analysis.

Data Intellegence Lead [Consulting]

07/2024 - Present

MagicPort Al

Working within the Maritime Intelligence team, consulting on data-related issues in the general maritime industry, such as identifying unique vessels from messy data and optimizing database management.

Visiting Assistant Professor

07/2020 - 02/2023

Hamilton College

Redesigned a series of data science courses, such as Statistical Analysis of Data, Statistical Modeling and Its Applications, and Statistical Methods in Machine Learning, by incorporating extensive coding into lectures, assessments, and projects. Actively participated in data science initiatives at Hamilton College, where one such initiative resulted in the creation of a data science major. Successfully engaged students in Machine Learning projects and played a crucial role in increasing the number of majors in mathematics and data science.

Coursera Instructor

2017 - Present

Coursera

Co-teaching Practical Time Series Analysis using R

Research Associate

2020, 2021

Air Force Research Lab Griffis Institute

Proved the existence of theoretical neural network solutions for differential equations, and designed and implemented numerical algorithms in Python to solve partial differential equations.

08/2015 - 05/2020

Tools

- Git/GitHub Actions
- AWS
- VS Code
- RStudio
- Terminal (Linux)
- Docker
- Posit Connect
- DBeaver
- Postman

Education

2008 - 2015

Ph.D and MA, Applied Mathematics

Indiana University

Bloomington, IN

2003 - 2008

BS, Mathematics

Boaziçi University

Istanbul, Turkey

Statistics Lecturer

Hamilton College

I developed and taught Statistical Analysis of Data using R

Applied Mathematics Lecturer and Math Service Coordinator

SUNY Polytechnic Institute

Promoted data analysis certificate by delivering technical lectures in various statistics and applied mathematics courses such as Applied Probability, Regression, and Time Series Analysis at undergraduate and graduate levels

Skills

- Languages
- Python, R, Bash, SQL
 - **Databases**
- PostgreSQL/Redshift, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite
 - DevOps
- Docker, GitHub Actions, Posit Connect
 - Cloud/AWS
- S3, EC2, Cognito, Redshift, Step Functions, Lambda, Glue, Secrets Manager, CloudWatch, ECS, Route 53
 - Web Development
- Streamlit, Shiny
- Machine Learning
- tidymodels, scikit-learn
- Data Handling
- Wrangling, Cleaning, Preprocessing, Feature Engineering
- Time Series Analysis
- ARIMA, SARIMA
- Statistical Inference & Visualization
- Reporting & Dashboarding
- Quarto, R Markdown, Jupyter Notebook, R Shiny

Awards and Grants

- Bronze Medal
- 44th International Mathematical Olympiad, Tokyo, Japan, 2003
 - Gold Medals
 - Azerbaijan Mathematical Olympiad, 2000, 2001, 2002, 2003
- **Summer Research Grants**
- Air Force Research Lab/Griffis Institute, 2021-22 (\$36,000)
- Dean's Pedagogical Development Awards
- Hamilton College, 2021-22 (\$4,500)
 - **Teaching Grant**
- Herkimer College and Hamilton College, 2022 (\$10,000)
 For teaching Financial Mathematics
 - SGU Award for Excellence in Teaching
- SUNY Poly, Academic Year 2018-19